# **Lindsay Montgomery, OLY**

Washington, DC 20008 | 520-664-6420 | lindsay.montgomery@olympian.org

Portfolio | GitHub | Blog | LinkedIn

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Full stack web developer with a background in Sales, Fintech, Tableau and Event Management. While working at Duke Law School, I began to write for loops to implement custom filters in Tableau dashboards and discovered my passion for problem solving. I quickly became hungry to learn how to code and expand my knowledge of tech. My experience at Flatiron School has solidified my ability to grasp concepts quickly, solve problems efficiently and has motivated me to never stop learning.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, React, Redux, SQL, PostgreSQL, APIs, GitHub, Object-Oriented-Programming, Object-Relational-Mapping, Tableau

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# BrackIt - Netlify | Demo | GitHub Frontend | GitHub Backend

A web application for any user looking to generate a bracket to keep track of a tournament, regardless of the activity (basketball, ping-pong, cornhole, etc.). BrackIt allows tournament hosts to create new tournaments and advance teams while participants can follow a tournament to view upcoming matchups or past results.

- Utilized Redux and Redux Thunk middleware to maintain a "single source of truth" and reuse functions across many child React components.
- Created a backend algorithm to generate a tournament bracket with the appropriate number of rounds and matchups based on the number of teams.
- Built a backend RESTful API with Ruby on Rails, stored in PostgreSQL
- Managed a complex join-table mapping of users to tournaments, to control permissions and allow "following" functionality

## GetTrails - Netlify | Demo | GitHub Frontend | GitHub Backend

A web application to help users keep track of trails they would like to hike, or their favorite trails. As a user you can save trails for future hikes, mark hikes completed, rate and favorite hikes.

- Seeded the local database with the Hiking Project API to implement RESTful routing and prevent heavy reliance on a third-party API.
- Integrated with the Google Maps API by inputting the longitude and latitude of a trail to display the trail location.
- Utilized JWT, bcrypt and localstorage to authorize users with encrypted information.
- Implemented AntDesign CSS framework for a friendly UI experience

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Duke Law Career and Professional Development Center**

Durham, NC

Data Analytics Coordinator, Recruiting Coordinator, Staff Specialist

02/2017 - 05/2019

- Provided the Career and Professional Development Center with efficient processes to track student employment data by utilizing Qualtircs surveys and developing Tableau dashboards to optimize career counselor's time.
- Lead law school staff-wide-trainings on Tableau and excel to encourage data visualization across offices.
- Built a WordPress website for the Career and Professional Development Center to communicate with students internally allowing the office to reduce mass emailing to students.
- Assisted the Employer Relations Director by tracking correspondence with employers, scheduling interviews and handling special requests for on campus interviewing programs and networking events.

# **Currency Capital**

Scottsdale, AZ

Account Executive, Junior Account Executive

06/2015 - 10/2016

- Funded 30+ deals with a combined gross margin of over \$200,000 to be promoted to Account Executive.
- Provided training to Junior Account Executives on database management to optimize sales calls and time.

## **EDUCATION**

# Flatiron School

Washington, DC

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript Program

03/ 2020 - 06/2020

**University of Iowa** 

Iowa City, IA

Bachelors of Arts, Sports Studies Major, Communications Studies Minor

05/ 2014

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Competed in the 200m Backstroke at the 2008 Olympic Games for Team Canada.